TRAN TRUNG TRUC

Website: viblo.asia/u/tructt2 GitHub: github.com/trungtruc123 Email: tieuthu.anninh@gmail.com Phone: +84 369224293

Experience with machine learning, deep learning and applications about Computer Vision, NLP, Speech. Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity. I like write blog share knowledge, experience about AI and participate in discussion about new development in AI techniques.

EXPERIENCE

FPT Software

Al Engineer 09/2020–Current

- Implement project Computer Vision, Nature Language Processing.
- Generate data use GAN, Variational AutoEncoders ,...
- Read, understand code AkaOCR to improve, update
- Get involved seminar reinforcement learning, optimizers, transformer for picture process.

FSERVING

Intern AI Engineer 03/2020–05/2020

- Implement virtual dressing room: remove background, detect pose, body measurements calculator
- Study openCV, algorithm machine learning
- Approach Computer Vision

DAC Viet Nam

Developer Python 01/2020–03/2020

- Implement web by framework FLASK
- Familiar environment linux, install CUDA
- Build app by Flutter
- Implement web, app recognition skin diseases

EDUCATION

DA Nang University 2016–2020

Major: Information Technology

Recognition error of battery

Build model object detection recognition error (foreign objects, bent, cracked, deformation) of battery:

- Gather data use : GAN, augmentation
- Build model one-shot-learning
- Train model, test
- Visualize results

Application product reviews on Lazada, Tiki based on comments

Use model BERT to sentiments analysis based on comments of customers:

- Crawl comment in Lazada, Tiki used BeautifulSoup, Selenium.
- Processing data use regular expression (regex).
- Train model, predict results use pretrain model BERT.

```
Github: https://github.com/trungtruc123/Review_Product_Lazada Blog:
```

https://viblo.asia/p/su-dung-ai-danh-gia-san-pham-tren-lazadatiki-dua-tren-comment-aWj53b9ol6m

Application web wrote poetry

Use model GPT-2 to generator poetry (6-8) Viet Nam:

- Crawl data poetry (Truyen Kieu, But Tre, thivien.net,...) from internet sources using Selenium
- Processing data use regex
- Tokenize data use pretrain model PhoBERT
- Fine-tuning model GPT-2
- Implement web demo by framework FLASK

```
Github: https://github.com/trungtruc123/Poemtry
Blog: https://viblo.asia/p/su-dung-ai-tri-tue-nhan-tao-sang-tac-tho-luc-bat-YWOZrj3RZQO
```

Application chatbot assistant covid-19 in facebook of hackathon contest

Build chatbot assistant covid-19 support updating news on the number of infected people in the world, how to prevent and hotlines,...

```
Github: https://github.com/trungtruc123/message_bot_fb
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0guSjRHEMK4
```

Application web optical character recognition vietnamese (handwritten)

```
Implement web recognition handwritten vietnamese address Github: https://github.com/trungtruc123/OCR_FLASK
```

Marker detection of parking car

Build model keypoint detection of parking car:

- Apply machine learning, albumentations generate 30k images
- Build DataLoader, custom model MSPN
- Train model, test
- Visualize results

Zalo object detection challenge contest

Build model object detection: RestinaNet, EfficientDet for traffic signs: rank 56

SKILLS

- Vision: Object detection, key-point detection, anomaly detection ...
- NLP : Sentiment Analysis , BERT, GPT-2, ...
- Data Structure, Database: MongoDB, MySQL
- Language: Python, C, C++, Java, JavaScript
- Deployment: Docker, API (Flask, Django)
- Framework: Pytorch, Tensorflow

Scholarships And Awards

University scholarship for talented program students

2017-2018

University scholarship for talented program students

2018-2019

Interests

- Write blog share knowledge, experience about AI.
- Participate in discussion about new development in AI techniques
- Build desire projects